<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- This file contains entities for the copyright and the legal notice. -->

<!-- CVS keywords
$Source$
$Author: amandel $
$Date: 2006-07-12 16:38:21 +0200 (Wed, 12 Jul 2006) $
$Revision: 255 $
$Name$
-->

<!ENTITY copyright_holder "
The jCoderZ.org Project. All rights reserved.">

<!ENTITY legal_notice "
<para>Redistribution and use in source and binary forms, with or without
modification, are permitted provided that the following conditions are
met:</para>

    <itemizedlist mark='opencircle'>
        <listitem>
           <para>Redistributions of source code must retain the above copyright
      notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer.</para>
         </listitem>

         <listitem>
           <para>Redistributions in binary form must reproduce the above
      copyright notice, this list of conditions and the following
      disclaimer in the documentation and/or other materials
      provided with the distribution.</para>
         </listitem>

         <listitem>
           <para>Neither the name of the jCoderZ.org Project nor the names of
      its contributors may be used to endorse or promote products
      derived from this software without specific prior written
      permission.</para>
         </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

<para>THIS MATERIAL IS PROVIDED BY THE REGENTS AND CONTRIBUTORS <quote>AS IS</quote> AND
ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE
IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR
PURPOSE ARE DISCLAIMED. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE REGENTS AND CONTRIBUTORS
BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, EXEMPLARY, OR
CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES (INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, PROCUREMENT OF
SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES; LOSS OF USE, DATA, OR PROFITS; OR
BUSINESS INTERRUPTION) HOWEVER CAUSED AND ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY,
WHETHER IN CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY, OR TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE OR
OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT OF THE USE OF THIS SOFTWARE, EVEN IF
ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE.</para>
">
