<chapter>
   <title>Introduction</title>

   <blockquote>
      <attribution>Donald Knuth, 
         <citetitle>Foreward to the book A=B</citetitle>
      </attribution>
      <para>
         Science is what we understand well enough 
         to explain to a computer. 
         Art is everything else we do.
      </para>
   </blockquote>

   <section>
      <title>Why Have Code Conventions</title>

      <para>Code conventions are important to programmers for a number of
      reasons:
         <itemizedlist mark='opencircle'>
            <listitem>
               <para>80% of the lifetime cost of a piece of software goes to
               maintenance.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
               <para>Hardly any software is maintained for its whole life by
               the original author.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
               <para>Code conventions improve the readability of the software,
               allowing engineers to understand new code more quickly and
               thoroughly.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
               <para>If you ship your source code as a product, you need to
               make sure it is as well packaged and clean as any other product
               you create.</para>
            </listitem>
         </itemizedlist>
      </para>
      <para>For the conventions to work, every person at jCoderZ.org  
		  writing software must conform to the code conventions.</para>
   </section>

   <section>
      <title>Acknowledgements</title>
      <para>This document is the result of the merger of 2 sources:
         <itemizedlist mark='opencircle'>

            <listitem>
               <para>Java Code Conventions from Sun. The original can be found
               at <ulink url="http://java.sun.com/docs/codeconv/"/> <citation>JavaCodeConv</citation>.</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
               <para>The former code conventions we where used to adhere.</para>
            </listitem>

         </itemizedlist>
      </para>
      
      <para>The document is maintained by the jCoderZ.org Project. 
		  Comments can be sent the web site at http://www.jcoderz.org/.
      </para>
   </section>

   <section>
      <title>Document content</title>

      <para>This document contains a list of rules ordered by different
      aspects. In general all given rules must be respected in order to 
      make the code more readable. 
      </para>
      <para>If conforming to these rules leads to code that is harder to read and
      understand, you might break these rules and choose another style for small
      parts of your code. You must prefer open standards when using another
      convention and document the convention and the reason for breaking these
      rules. 
      </para>
      <para>The inability to conform to this guideline might be a strong
      indication that the given code approach could be enhanced. To avoid major 
      rework tasks, please get in contact with any member of the jCoderZ.org
      Project in order to get assistance for the given coding problem.
      </para>

      <para>If you are faced with a problem that is not covered by any of the 
      rules in this document, get in contact with the jCoderZ.org Project or 
      use the referred document to identify a solution. 
      </para>
      
      <para>The Book <citetitle>Writing Robust Java Code</citetitle>
      <citation>Ambler00</citation>
      is a reading recommendation and gives a good introduction for novice and 
      advanced software engineers.
      </para>
      <para>Conformance to this coding guideline will automatically be checked 
      by <ulink url="http://checkstyle.sourceforge.net/">Checkstyle</ulink>. 
      If non-conforming code is detected, the code author will be contacted 
      and asked to enhance his source code. 
      </para>
   </section>

</chapter>
