<chapter>
   <title>Comments</title>

   <section>
      <title>Implementation Comments</title>

      <para>Implementation comments are those which are delimited by 
      <classname>/*...*/</classname> and <classname>//</classname>.

      They are means for commenting out code or for
      adding information about the particular implementation. 
      Doc comments are meant to describe the specification of the code, 
      from an implementation-independent
      perspective. It is meant for developers who might not necessarily have the
      source code at hand. 
      </para>
      <para>Comments should be used to give an overview of the code
      and provide additional information that are not readily available in the
      code itself. Comments should contain only information that are relevant
      to reading and understanding the program. For example, information about
      how to build the corresponding package or in what directory it resides
      should not be stated as a comment.</para>

      <para>Discussions of non-trivial or non-obvious design decisions are
      appropriate, but avoid duplicating information that is present and 
      clearly visible in the code. Redundant comments get outdated too easily.
      In general, avoid any comments that are likely to
      get outdated as the code evolves.</para>

      <para>Note: A high frequency of comments sometimes reflects poor quality of
      code. When you feel compelled to add a comment, consider rewriting the
      code to make it clearer. Comments must not be enclosed in large boxes
      drawn with asterisks or other characters.</para>
   </section>

   <section>
      <title>Documentation Comments</title>

      <para>Doc comments describe Java classes, interfaces, constructors,
      methods, and fields. Each doc comment is set inside the comment
      delimiters <classname>/**...*/</classname>.
      
         <informalexample>
            <programlisting>&ExampleClass;</programlisting>
         </informalexample>
      </para>

      <para>The first line of doc comments
      (<classname>/**</classname>) for classes and interfaces is not indented.
      Subsequent doc comment lines each have 1 space of indentation (to
      vertically align the asterisks). Members, including constructors, have
      three spaces for the first doc comment line and four spaces thereafter.
      Doc comments should not be positioned inside a method or constructor
      definition block, because Java associates documentation comments with
      the first declaration after the comment.</para>

      <para>Doc comments for classes or interfaces must include the 
      <classname>@author</classname> tag. Only one name per @author tag in the
      form <classname>@author</classname> <emphasis>firstname lastname</emphasis>.
      Developers making major changes on the file must 
      add their name.

      For methods or constructors the
      <classname>@param</classname>, <classname>@return</classname>, 
      <classname>@throws</classname>, <classname>@see</classname> tag
      must be included as needed. 
      Do not use the <classname>@exception</classname> tag.
      
      A <classname>package.html</classname> must be added for each new package.
      </para>

      <para>
      For further details, see 
      <ulink url="http://java.sun.com/j2se/javadoc/writingdoccomments/index.html">
      How to Write Doc Comments for Javadoc</ulink>
      which includes information on the doc comment tags and for details about 
      doc comments and javadoc, see the
      <ulink url="http://java.sun.com/j2se/javadoc/">Javadoc Tool Home Page.</ulink>
      </para>

   </section>

</chapter>
