<chapter>

   <title>Programming Practices</title>

   <section>

      <title>Referring to Class Variables and Methods</title>

      <para>Do not use an object to access a class (static) variable or
      method. Use a class name instead.
      <informalexample>
         <programlisting>&ReferringSample;</programlisting>
      </informalexample>
      </para>

   </section>

   <section>

      <title>Constants</title>

      <para>Numerical constants (literals) must not be coded directly (magic numbers),
      except for -1, 0, and 1, which can appear in a
      <classname>for</classname> loop as counter values.</para>

   </section>

   <section>

      <title>Parenthesis</title>

      <para>It is generally a good idea to use parentheses liberally in
      expressions involving mixed operators to avoid operator precedence
      problems. Even if the operator precedence seems clear to you,
      it might not be to others.  Do not assume that other programmers
      know precedence as well as you do.</para>

   </section>

   <section>

      <title>Returning Values</title>

      <para>You should have only one exit point in a method. You must have a good
      explanation if you use more than one return statement in a method.</para>

   </section>

   <section>

      <title>Special Comments</title>

      <para>Use <classname>TODO</classname> in a comment to flag something
      that is bogus but works. Use <classname>FIXME</classname> to flag
      something that is bogus and broken.</para>

   </section>

   <section>

      <title>Initialization</title>

      <para>Initialize local variables where they are declared. The
      only reason not to initialize a variable in its declaration is if the
      initial value depends on some computation that has to occur first.</para>

   </section>

   <section>
      <title>Size Contraints</title>
      
      <para>Methods are limited to 100 lines of code. 
      Empty lines and single line comments are ignored.</para>

      <para>The number of arguments for an method or constructor must not
      exceed 7.
      </para>
      
   </section>

   <section>
      <title>Empty Blocks</title>
      
      <para>Intentionally empty block must contain a comment. Empty blocks that
         can/should never be reached like empty catch or default block
         must throw a RuntimeException.</para>
   </section>

</chapter>
